Hero, have you had enough sleep? Get up now.
勇者你睡够了没 快起床
Breakfast is ready.
早餐已经准备好了
You're too laid back. Max.
未免太悠哉了吧 麦克斯
Max?
麦克斯
Is he not breathing?
没有呼吸了吗
Hey… Hero, pull yourself together.
喂…勇者你振作点
(Level 1 Demon Lord and One Room Hero)
《Lv1魔王与独居废勇者》
(Episode 2: Watch out for the Glasses Girl)
(#2 务必小心眼镜女)
Are you going out?
你要出门吗
Where are you going?
去哪里
I have some errands to run.
去办点事
Be more specific.
什么事
Then I'll go with you.
朕跟你一起去
Why? Don't come with me. So annoying.
为什么 不准跟来 烦死了
What kind of attitude is that?
你那是什么口气
Is it so embarrassing to go out with me?
跟朕站在一起有那么丢脸吗
Don't say the kind of things only an old lady would say.
不要说那种老妈才会讲的话
Who would dare take a demon out and wander around?
谁敢带魔族出去乱晃啊
Hide your third eye and horns if you want to go out.
想出门的话 至少先想办法藏住第三只眼和角
It's too suspicious.
太可疑了
By the way, what does that guy usually do?
话说回来 那家伙平常都在忙什么
Is he going for special training to fight me again?
莫非是准备跟我等再次交战 跑去哪里做特训
I need to make it clear.
朕必须立刻去确认清楚才行
Right.
对了
I'll use my best transfiguration magic to hide my identity.
就用朕最拿手的变身魔法 隐藏身分吧
After all, transfiguration is the hobby of the Demon Lord.
毕竟变身是魔王的嗜好
But what kind of appearance should I change into?
不过朕该变成什么样的外貌
Right, Zenia said this outfit is a school uniform.
对了 洁妮亚说这身是学生服
So it's most appropriate for me to change into an age similar to a student.
那么变成与学生相仿的年龄 应该最为妥当
Transfigure.
变身
Hmm, perfect.
好 完美
If I let my guard down, the magic might be dispelled.
一旦松懈了 魔法搞不好会解除
I must be cautious.
要小心为上
In ten years, the human realm has changed dramatically.
仔细一看 人类们在十年间确实变了个面貌
The number of skyscrapers has grown.
高楼大厦也增加了
HIGH-PAYING PART-TIME JOB, MONEY LOVER Transportation tools have also advanced.
(高薪打工 最爱钱) -像那种交通工具也变得发达 -甜蜜糖果…征人…
-Welcome. What would you like to eat? -Human technology is truly impressive.
-欢迎光临 要吃什么 -人类的技术能力果然不容小觑
-Please give me one.
-请给我一份
-So sexy… -Look at that.
-超猛的… -你看
PRIVATE ROOM, 24-HOUR MOVIE APPRECIATION What kind of shop is this?
(独立包厢 影片鉴赏) 这间是什么店
I see. So humans can watch movies in the shop.
原来如此 可以在店里看电影之类的
But this kind of thing can be watched at home too, right?
不过这种东西在家里也可以看吧
Damn Max.
臭麦克斯
Don't think you can hide from my eyes.
别以为你躲得过朕的双眼
He should be nearby.
应该就在这附近
Found him.
找到了
Great, start following him.
好极了 开始追踪
Let me reveal your secret, you scumbag hero.
看朕揭发你的秘密 混蛋勇者
He goes into that shop.
他进去那间店了
He comes out immediately. What did he buy?
这么快就出来 他买了什么
He starts drinking right away.
马上就打开了
This is definitely not special training.
绝对不是特训
Is he planning to spend the whole day like this?
他打算就这样度过一整天吗
Found him… Hey, hero.
找到了… 勇者
What?
什么
Hi.
嗨
That's great.
太好了
There are still people who admire Max as a hero.
还是有人把麦克斯当作勇者崇拜
Let's play soccer, hero.
来踢足球吧 勇者
Again? I don't know what to do with you guys.
怎么又要踢 真拿你们没辙
You've started drinking again. You're so useless.
你又开喝了 有够废
Since you are tall, hero, it is the three of us against you.
勇者个子大 那就我们三人对你一人吧
Alright, bring it on.
好啊 放马过来
How is it? If you can snatch the ball, then come and snatch it.
怎么样啊 抢得到的话就来抢啊
Hero, you're so cunning. Don't be serious with kids.
勇者 你太狡猾了 大人不要跟小孩认真比啦
Take this.
看我的
Ouch!
好痛
How dare you kick me!
竟敢踢我
Brat, take this!
这个臭小鬼 看招
Listen up.
听好了
Ten years ago, I did this, that, and this to defeat the demon army.
十年前我可是这样那样再这样 收拾了魔族大军
Really?
真的假的
At his age, it is not strange at all to have such a big child.
其实以他现在的年纪 有这么大的小孩也不奇怪
Yosuke.
洋介
Oh no, it's my mom.
糟了 是我妈
Hero, everyone, I'm sorry. I have to go home.
勇者 大家 抱歉我先回去了
Take care.
路上小心
Um… I'm going home, too.
那…我也先回家了
I see.
这样啊
Actually, my mom told me not to play with the hero.
其实我妈妈说"不准跟勇者玩"
You should listen to your mom.
最好还是乖乖听妈妈的话
My family did not say anything, so I will play with you when I want. Here you go.
我的家人没特别说什么 想玩的时候再来陪你玩 拿去
Thanks.
谢啦
I'm leaving, I'll say hello to mom for you.
先走啰 我帮你跟妈妈打声招呼
No need.
不必了
Why doesn't he go home to sleep if he wants to?
要睡干嘛不回家睡
I can't stand it. I'll go home and prepare dinner.
真受不了 我先回去准备晚餐好了
Old man.
大叔
If you sleep here, you will really bother the people who live nearby.
你在这边睡觉 会害附近的居民困扰好吗
Get up now.
给我起来啊
What kind of reaction is that?
那是什么反应
Stinky old man, stand up.
臭大叔 给我站起来
What do you want, brat?
想怎样 小鬼头
Don't you know who I am?
你不知道本大爷是谁吗
Who would know? You just seem like a suspicious person.
鬼才知道 只是个可疑的家伙吧
How can the authorities let this kind of guy go free?
行政机关怎么会放任这种家伙不管
Let us show you how to become a different person.
我们来教教你 怎么重新做人吧
Come on, bring it on.
来啊 放马过来啊
What, are you scared?
怎么啦 怕了吗
HERO MAX IS VIOLENT AGAINST CIVILIANS?
(勇者麦克斯 对普通人施暴)
N-No.
不…不行
Max, you must not fight back.
麦克斯 绝对不能还手
You guys aren't worth my fist.
你们这种货色不值得我动拳头
Go home if you are satisfied now, brat.
满足了就回家去吧 小弟弟
You're quite cool, huh?
还挺帅的嘛
What a cool guy.
够猛喔
Go die.
给我去死
People like you are a loss to society simply by existing.
你这种人光是活着 就会对社会带来不利
Apologize now. Apologize to the world, you trash.
快道歉啊 向这个世界道歉 垃圾
Take this punch.
再来一拳啊
It's my hypnotic spell, Sleep Mind.
是朕的催眠咒语 "渴睡之意"
Don't worry, I didn't hurt them.
无须担心 他们毫发无伤
Since you were watching, why didn't you help earlier?
既然在旁边看 干嘛不早点出来帮忙
Sorry.
抱歉
I didn't mean to let you be humiliated.
朕无意害你被人羞辱
It's fine, you understand now, right?
没关系啦 这下子你也明白了吧
I'm not a hero anymore.
我已经不是勇者了
I am just a man who drinks in the middle of the day,
只会大白天喝酒
brags in front of kids,
在小孩子面前得意洋洋地吹嘘
gets annoyed by those brats, and cannot do anything about it.
最后还被那种小伙子缠上 却什么都做不了
In my heart, I am terrified.
心里其实怕得要命
I'm such an embarrassment.
简直丢人现眼
That's not true.
没有那回事
I admire that you didn't fight back.
朕佩服你没有动手打回去
You're amazing.
非常了不起
Aren't you too lenient with me?
你会不会对我太宽容了
"Go home if you are satisfied now, brat."
"满足了就回家去吧 小弟弟"
You jerk.
你这混蛋
I think you were cool.
朕觉得你那样很帅啊
Alright, let's go home and eat. What should we cook?
好了 回家吃饭吧 要煮什么呢
I'll go somewhere else and be back before dinner.
我去别的地方晃晃 开饭前会回去
Where are you going?
你要去哪里
I have some errands to run.
去办点事
Really?
是吗
He's such a handful.
真拿他没办法
What do you want to eat?
你想吃什么
Hamburger.
汉堡排好了
For the sides, let's do potatoes and green beans.
配菜就弄马铃薯和四季豆
We should still have carrots at home, right?
家里应该还有胡萝卜吧
Perfect.
好极了
But where did that hero go?
不过勇者那家伙到底绕去哪里了
I hope he didn't go drinking again.
希望他不会又跑去喝酒
PRIVATE ROOM, MOVIE APPRECIATION
(独立包厢 影片鉴赏)
What's the deal with that woman?
那个女的是怎样
Her outfit is so exaggerated.
穿得有够夸张
I'm back.
我回来了
Should we cook and eat now?
要不要现在就煮饭吃
A ridiculously dressed woman was just passing by.
刚才路上有个打扮超离谱的女人
Really? I didn't see such a girl.
是吗 朕没有看到那样的女生
She was outrageous, almost naked.
真的超猛 跟全裸没两样
Geez. How degenerate has human society become?
真是的 人类的风纪到底有多败坏
It's done. Let's eat with gratitude.
煮好了 心存感激地吃吧
Hey, why didn't you say "Let's dig in"?
真是的 怎么没说"我要开动了"
Alright, let's dig in.
好啦 我要开动了
We have a guest.
有客人
Wait a minute. No sneaking bites.
你等一下 不可以偷吃
You do not need to open the door because it is most likely a salesperson.
不必开门啦 反正八成又是来推销的
Who is it?
请问是哪位
Your Majesty… Thank goodness you're safe…
陛下…幸好您平安无事…
What? It's Zenia.
什么嘛 原来是洁妮亚
Didn't I tell you to wait in the castle?
朕不是叫妳留在城堡等吗
You said you'd be right back and had me prepare dinner.
是您自己说马上回来 还叫我准备晚餐耶
Her appetite is still astonishing.
她的食量还是一样惊人
Even our dinner is going to be eaten up.
连我们的晚餐都要被吃光了
Your Majesty's cooking has the flair of a demon realm ruler, as expected.
不愧是陛下 厨艺也具有统治魔界的王者风范
She ate everything.
吃到一口都不剩
What can we do?
没办法
I'll go buy more food later.
等一下再去买点东西吧
It's getting more and more delicious.
忍不住吃个不停
Do you have any toothpicks?
请问一下 有没有牙签之类的
What's with this woman?
这女人是怎样
I'm sorry for the commotion.
抱歉吵吵闹闹的
Her name is Zenia.
她叫做洁妮亚
She's my secretary.
是朕的秘书官
A secretary? This kind of person? Is she really capable of the job?
秘书 这种家伙吗 这女的有办法胜任吗
You are so rude.
太失礼了
I am a loyal servant to His Majesty.
我是对陛下忠心耿耿的仆人
With admiration for His Majesty, I, Zenia, have walked for three days and nights
抱着我对陛下的仰慕之情
from the royal city through mountains and rivers.
本人洁妮亚从王城跋山涉水而来 走了三天三夜
She actually walked here?
居然用走的
She must not have thought about using human transportation.
她肯定没想过 可以搭人类的交通工具
This journey was extremely difficult.
这段旅途无比艰辛
People on the streets pointed and whispered about me.
街上的人类对我指指点点
Some laughed at me, some frowned.
有人嘲笑我 有人紧皱眉头
I face discrimination simply because I am a demon.
只因为我是魔之眷属 就无缘无故遭到歧视
No, it's probably because of your outfit.
不 是因为妳的服装吧
Let's go, Your Majesty.
走吧 陛下
Please follow me back to the city immediately.
请马上跟我回城里
Why are you suddenly saying this?
怎么冷不防说这些
Your Majesty, spending too much time with this destitute hero may make you a fool.
跟这种落魄勇者相处久了 小心变成蠢蛋
Zenia,
洁妮亚
How can you say that when you broke into someone's house and ate there?
妳闯进别人家还吃了一顿饭 怎么可以讲那种话
Besides, I am staying here to personally experience human society.
更何况朕留在这里 是为了亲自接触人类社会
This place is like a base for gathering information.
此地可谓用来搜集情报的据点
Although you say that, Your Majesty,
陛下您嘴上那么说
I have already deduced your true intentions, you are obsessed,
属下早已看透 您其实是执着于…
-no, infatuated with this useless man. -U-Useless man?
-不 倾心于这个废物男人 -废物…废物男
Don't say it in such a harsh way.
别用那么恶心的讲法
I thought you would go home after learning about the hero's situation.
还以为您得知勇者的现况后 就会立刻打道回府
I never thought things would turn out like this…
没想到会变成这样
Take him back with you, I don't mind.
妳带他回去 我也无所谓
What are you talking about? You can't do anything on your own.
你说什么 明明一个人什么都不会做
If I go back, you will die right away, you life idiot.
朕要是回去了 你这个生活白痴马上就会死掉
I wouldn't die, you know.
不至于死掉啦
Alright.
好吧
In that case,
既然如此
I will sever Your Majesty's attachment to the hero here.
我就在这里斩断 陛下对勇者的留恋
Come on, hero. Prepare yourself.
来吧 勇者 做好觉悟吧
She's even wearing brass knuckles. Seriously?
还戴手指虎 骗人的吧
Zenia's savagery is quite a headache for me.
真是野蛮 令人头疼
I thought she was good at magic.
我还以为她是擅长魔法的类型
Zenia has no talent for magic at all.
洁妮亚没有半点魔法的天赋
So that's why she walked here?
所以才会徒步过来吗
What are you two whispering about?
在那边窃窃私语什么
If you don't make a move, I'll attack.
不出招的话 我就要进攻了
You're her boss, do something to stop her.
这位上司 你倒是阻止一下啊
Forget it, you can't beat him anyway.
算了吧 妳是敌不过他的
Stop it.
住手
Have you had enough, you shrew?
闹够了没有 妳这个泼妇
Don't you remember how many soldiers like you I've defeated before?
也不想想我以前砍了几个 像妳这种程度的小兵
Max,
麦克斯
she's still an unmarried girl. Don't scare her.
人家是还没嫁人的少女 不要吓坏她
Alright… I'm sorry.
好啦…真抱歉
You're also at fault, Zenia.
妳也有错 洁妮亚
If Max really gets serious, you won't end up well.
要是麦克斯认真起来 妳肯定不会有好下场
Okay, you should apologize now.
好了 快点道歉
I-I'm sorry.
对…对不起
You really apologized. You're so honest.
真的道歉了 妳还真是老实
Okay, His Majesty's interest in you makes sense given your strength.
好吧 实力如此强大 难怪陛下如此着迷
Even though you're an enemy, you're still admirable.
虽然是敌人 依旧值得佩服
Right?
对吧…
What stance are these guys taking while talking?
这些家伙 到底是站在什么立场说这些
You're all sweaty, Zenia.
妳弄得一身汗耶 洁妮亚
Yeah, I've walked a long way.
是啊 毕竟走了好长一段路
Do you want to take a bath?
要不要去洗个澡
Can I? Then please let me use it.
可以吗 麻烦了
Won't you ask the house owner?
不问一下屋主吗
I'm sorry, my subordinate has caused you trouble.
真抱歉 部下给你添麻烦了
Yeah. Geez.
就是说啊 真是的
Her punch is really powerful.
那记拳头威力真强
It's probably 30 times the power of those thugs from before.
大概是上次的小混混乘以30人吧
If the opponent wasn't you, it would have been dangerous.
若对手不是你 那就危险了
You must be having a difficult time with someone like her as your secretary.
不过你也真辛苦 居然是那种人当秘书
Don't you have any other options?
没有其他人选吗
Zenia may be a bit of a blockhead, but…
洁妮亚的确有点少根筋 但是…
Her intelligence-gathering ability is unquestionable.
她的情报搜集能力是无庸置疑的
She had a pretty good grasp of your evaluation beforehand.
事前也大致掌握了你的评价
Your Majesty, thank you. The hot bath was so comfortable.
陛下 谢谢您 洗热水澡真舒服
Very good…
很好…
At least say thank you to me.
都不会谢谢我吗
Although it's a bit shabby here, you can rest well here.
虽然这里有点寒酸 但妳慢慢坐
You can take drinks from the fridge.
冰箱里的饮料可以拿去喝喔
Thank you for your hospitality, Your Majesty.
谢谢您的招待 陛下
Whatever.
你们高兴就好
I'm so hungry.
肚子好饿
That's true.
说得也是
Well, I'll go get some food.
那朕去买点吃的回来
Zenia, you are a guest now.
洁妮亚 妳现在是客人
You need to get along with Max, okay?
要跟麦克斯好好相处喔
Y-Yes, Your Majesty.
遵…遵命 陛下
-Wait, take me with you… -I'm leaving.
-等一下 带我一起去… -朕出门啰
Uh…
呃…
I've also finished investigating your love scandals so far.
你至今的桃色丑闻我也调查完毕了
You are reckless and flirting everywhere, one after the other.
一个接一个 毫无节操 到处拈花惹草
Listen up.
听好了
If you dare to put your evil hands on His Majesty, I will not let you go.
敢对陛下伸出魔掌 我绝对不会放过你
What are you talking about? Nonsense.
妳到底在讲什么 莫名其妙
Let me make it clear.
我把话说清楚
Do not think that just because you won today means you have won against me.
可别以为刚才那样过招 就等于是你赢了我
If it weren't for His Majesty's presence,
要不是陛下在场
I would have already punched you into meat sauce.
我早就挥拳把你剁成肉酱
Is that so?
是喔…
Hey you.
我说你啊
What kind of attitude is that?
你那是什么态度
Listen to me carefully. What kind of hero are you? Big dummy.
专心听我说话啊 算什么勇者 大笨蛋
Why did you suddenly grab me? What's wrong with you?
妳干嘛突然抓我 怎么了
You can't escape. Hey.
休想逃跑 喂
Is that alcohol in your hand?
妳手上那罐是酒吗
People who get drunk after one drink shouldn't drink.
喝一罐就醉 还敢喝酒
Stop drinking. Stop it now.
别再喝了 快停下来
You're so noisy. Jerk.
吵死人了 混蛋
S-Sorry, I didn't mean to.
抱…抱歉 我不是故意的
Please do not sue me, I beg you.
拜托别告我 算我求妳
Where is the tea?
茶呢…
It hurts.
好痛
You're pretty bold, huh?
你胆子不小嘛
Are you prepared?
做好觉悟了没
I get it already! Let's have some tea first.
我知道了啦 先喝个茶
And you should put on some clothes.
然后妳先穿件衣服吧
Go die.
去死
What's with this speed?
速度太快了吧
Shoot, she's going to break the house.
糟了 会被她打烂
Stop right there.
给我站住
Don't chase me!
不要追上来
Go put on your clothes, idiot.
去穿衣服啦 蠢蛋
That person is naked. It's so strange.
光溜溜的 好奇怪
Don't look.
不可以看
Don't you think he looks familiar?
不觉得他很眼熟吗
So funny.
超搞笑的
Why is it so noisy?
怎么那么吵闹
Given that you are already drunk,
看妳已经醉醺醺的
your body must be out of control, right?
身体也不听使唤了吧
Don't underestimate me.
请不要小看我
I told you I'd turn you into meat sauce.
就说要把你剁成肉酱了
Is that so?
是吗
Well, then I won't hold back either.
那我也不会手下留情
I will show you the true power of a hero.
让妳见识一下勇者的真本事
Excuse me for a moment.
不好意思打扰一下
How can you run naked in the streets?
怎么可以光着身体在街上奔跑
Can I ask you a few questions?
能不能请教几个问题
I am sorry, I am truly sorry.
抱歉 真的很对不起
It's such a headache.
真是伤脑筋
Why is she not wearing clothes but wearing brass knuckles?
怎么没穿衣服 只戴手指虎
Are you okay? She was pursuing you.
您没事吧 看您被她追着跑
I'm fine…
我没事…
Well, I'm sorry.
那个 不好意思
Actually, I know her.
其实我认识她
I gave her some alcohol and she got excited.
给她喝了酒 她一时兴奋过头
The brass knuckles are mine too, I'm really sorry.
手指虎也是我的 非常抱歉
I'm so sorry for causing you trouble.
非常对不起 给你添了麻烦
Don't worry about it.
别在意了
Mr. Max,
麦克斯先生
you were very active ten years ago.
您在十年前非常活跃
It's because of you that we have the world we have now.
正因为有您 才有现在的世界
I'm truly grateful.
感激不尽
You recognized me, huh?
还是穿帮了吗
I'm sorry that I'm like this now.
真抱歉 现在却是这副德性
Please allow me to apologize again for what happened last night.
请容许朕再次为昨晚的事致歉
My subordinate caused such a mess.
部下居然闯下大祸
Don't worry about it.
别放在心上
Did she go back in the end?
结果她回去了吗
To tell you the truth…
不瞒你说…
Here it comes.
来了啊
What's up? Did you order something?
怎么啦 你订了东西吗
I'm Zenia from room 205.
我是住在205号室的洁妮亚
I just moved next door, so I came to say hello.
刚搬到隔壁 因此过来打声招呼
Are you done with the procedure?
手续都办完了吗
Yes, I applied for immediate occupancy.
是的 毕竟是即日入住
What did you say? You moved here? And staying next door?
妳说什么 搬来了 还搬到隔壁
Even after what happened yesterday,
虽然昨天发生了那样的事
I still do not trust you.
但我还是认为你这男人不可信
If something happens to His Majesty, it would be terrible.
要是陛下有什么万一 那就糟了
So I will be along to monitor you
因此我将随同监视
and collect information about the human realm along the way.
顺便搜集一下人界的情报
Is gathering information just a side thing?
搜集情报只是顺便的吗
Excellent.
好极了
This apartment will be the stepping stone for future invasions.
这间公寓将是日后侵略的垫脚石
Please spare me.
拜托饶了我吧
I hope we can get along, Your Majesty
还请多多指教 陛下
and Mr. Max.
以及麦克斯先生
Is this woman from the demon clan?
这个女的…是魔族吗
Pretty interesting, Mr. Max.
挺有意思的嘛 麦克斯先生